IGNACIO SALINAS

COMPUTER SCIENCE ENGINEER DATA SCIENCE MASTER STUDENT

PROFILE

Extensive knowledge of C/C++, Java and Python, with solid skills for collection, analysis and management of data. I am very used to work under pressure and meet deadlines. Flexible and highly adaptable for teamwork and collaborative projects. I am a very detailed and imaginative person not only at work but also in my personal technical projects. When something does not work as expected, I have experience, and success so far, in finding innovative and out of the box solutions which solve te problem.

PRO SKILLS

C. C++, PYTHON

JAVA, SQL, R, MACHINE LEARNING, AWS, QT DATA SCIENCE

OTHERS (ASSEMBLER, HTML, CSS, ANDROID STUDIO, ETC.)

PERSONAL SKILLS

- QUICK LEARNING CAPACITY
- GREAT WORK CAPACITY
- TRUSTWORTHY
- GOOD TEAM PLAYER
- RESPONSABILITY

SS LANGUAGE

- SPANISH (MOTHER TONGUE)
- ENGLISH

INTERESTS

DATA MINING TRAVELING ANIMALS IOT

FOOTBALL SOCIAL MEDIA SURFING CYCLING

WORK EXPERIENCE

MADRID. SPAIN

TECHNOLOGY CONSULTANT I

OCT 2021 - PRESENT

SOFTWARE ENGINEER & DATA SCIENTIST

MAY 2021 - PRESENT

SOFTWARE ENGINEER SEPT 2019 - MAY 2021

EDUCATION

DATA SCIENCE MASTER SEP 2020 - PRESENT

COMPUTER SCIENCES DEGREE SEP 2016 - JUN 2020

BACCALAUREATE - SCIENCES & TECHNOLOGY

SEP 2014 - JUN 2016

FIRST CERTIFICATE IN ENGLISH -LEVEL B2

MARCH 2016

AWARDS

INCLUDED IN THE 2021 SEDEA RANKING OCTOBER 2021

FINALIST UNIVERSITYHACK DATATHON 2021 **MARCH 2021**

X2 BEST E.P.S. BACHELOR THESIS SEPT 2020 AND FEB 2021

X3 EXCELLENCE SCHOLARSHIP JAN 2020, 2019, 2018

TOP 5 BEST FIRST YEAR STUDENTS SEPTEMBER 2018

PROJECTS

MY SMART HOME + VIRTUAL ASSISTANT **ABOUT TO START**

> MY SMART HOME JAN 2018 - PRESENT

AGRO ANALYSIS FEB 2021 - MARCH 2021

MECHANICAL ARM APR 2020 - MAY 2020

REFERENCES

DR. EDUARDO LAGE NEGRO PROFESSOR AND SCIENTIST AT UAM.

Phone: +34 636 355 443 Email: eduardo.lage@uam.es

HEWLETT PACKARD ENTERPRISE

Create and deliver technology solutions for telecommunications companies.

PLENOPTIKA EUROPE

+34 648 618 010

Development of a cloud machine learning engine to predict refractive errors using Python and AWS.

SALINASSANCHEZNACHO@GMAIL.COM

MEDIC, WWW.MEDICUAM.COM

Developed a calibration system for a visual simulation device (SimVis) using C++ and Qt. The project includes both software (bluetooth, image processing and low-level camera control modules) and hardware (design of different parts of the system, build the calibration cradle, etc.).

AUTONOMOUS UNIVERSITY OF MADRID (UAM)

AUTONOMOUS UNIVERSITY OF MADRID (UAM) Average mark: 8.94/10.

I.E.S MARÍA DE CÓRDOBA, LAS NAVAS DEL MARQUÉS (ÁVILA) Average mark: 9.35/10.

ACADEMIA DE IDIOMAS LAS NAVAS, LAS NAVAS DEL MARQUÉS (ÁVILA)

SEDEA, WWW.SEDEA.ES

The Spanish Society of Academic Excellence (SEDEA) is a national entity whose main mission is to identify and accredit the best graduates in the country.

CAJAMAR, WWW.CAJAMARDATALAB.COM

5th place. Cajamar Universityhack is the largest data analytics competition in Spain.

EVERIS (WWW.EVERIS.COM) AND DELOITTE (WWW.DELOITTE.COM)

Chosen between all the bachelor thesis of the academic year 2019/2020.

COMMUNITY OF MADRID

Excellence scholarship granted to the best students of the academic year in Madrid.

AUTONOMOUS UNIVERSITY OF MADRID

Award granted to the 5 best students of the first course of Computer Science Engineering.

ADD A VIRTUAL ASSISTANT TO MY 'SMART HOME' PROJECT

Add the possibility to control 'My smart home' from a virtual assistant such as Google home or Amazon

BASED ON TELEGRAM + RASPBERRY PI

Used python to create a domotic system for a single-family house. To see more, press the play button.

CHALLENGE CAJAMAR AGRO ANALYSIS 🖈

Used python to make an analysis of the Spanish market during the pandemic. Click the link!.

UNIVERSITY PROJECT

Used C++ and an arduine to create a mechanical arm. To see more, press the play button.

CARLOS S. HERNÁNDEZ TORRES DIRECTOR OF ENGINEERING AT PLENOPTIKA.

Phone: +34 691 729 094 Email: carlos@plenoptika.com